LUCY: Life was given to us
a billion years ago.
What have we done with it?
Lucy.
It's easy as pie. In and
out, all done and dusted.
And why don't
you do it yourself?
The last thing
the guy's expecting
is a total 10 turning
up to deliver the case.
It'll blow his mind.
Come on!
What's in it?
(CHUCKLING) Sweetheart!
Don't get paranoid
on me, all right?
You trust me, don't you?
(UPBEAT DANCE MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALL WHOOPING)
Fuck!
Richard, I really do like you.
But I have to take care
of myself right now.
I don't know. I've got to
concentrate on so many things.
Hey, hey.
What are you doing?
I'm going home, because
I have exams on Monday.
I have to shower
and I have to study, okay?
You know what? The other
day, I was in this museum.
And you know what I found out?
What?
The first ever woman
was named Lucy.
Is that supposed to
make me feel better?
Yeah.
No.
I'll call you. Okay?
Okay, okay, okay.
I'll be honest with you.
I can't deliver the case myself.
I had a little falling-out
with the guy.
It's nothing major, but if
it's you, problem solved.
You walk in there, you
go up to the reception,
you ask for Mr. Jang
to come down.
He comes down,
he takes the case,
you flash him
your prettiest smile
and bounce.
Look! You can even see
the reception from here.
Come on.
What's in the case?
I don't know, it's
just some paperwork.
Yeah? Let's see it then.
It's locked. And only Mr.
Jang has the code.
(SCOFFS) I'm just
the delivery boy.
Do you get paid to do this?
Yeah, kind of.
Like how much?
Okay! We are
negotiating now or...
No, no. How much do you get paid?
I want to know how much.
A thousand dollars.
You get paid a thousand dollars
for delivering paperwork?
Really?
I don't know. It takes me 10
minutes and they pay me a grand
and the rest is
none of my business.
Well, it's none of my business
either, I'll tell you now.
Listen!
What?
We split it down
the middle. Hmm?
(SIGHS)
That's 500 for you, and 500 for me.
Richard, I will call you.
Listen, it's the third
time this week,
I'm showing up in the same
hotel, with the same cowboy hat.
Oh.
(IN SOUTHERN ACCENT)
Problem solved!
(IN NORMAL VOICE) Go, go.
I'll wait for you. Go.
Lucy, honey...
I've done this a dozen times.
It's paperwork.
It's probably just some designs
they switched so
they can copy them.
That's how it works
in this country.
Even my Stetson
was made here. Look.
Says so on the label,
"Made in Taiwan."
(IN SOUTHERN ACCENT) So long,
cowboy with the fake Stetson.
Baby, please.
(IN NORMAL VOICE) Richard, I got to go.
And seriously...
What the hell are you doing?
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry. I really
need your help.
Stop! Stop it! Take
this off me right now!
I can't. Take this
off me right now!
I can't, Mr. Jang's the
only one who has the key.
All you have to do
is go into the hotel
and ask for him
at the reception.
No! Take it off me
right now!
I'm so sorry. I really
have no choice.
The sooner you go in, the
sooner you'll be back out!
I can't believe
you did this to me.
I'll be right here.
You have my word.
Your word isn't worth shit!
It's worth 500 bucks, up front.
You're an asshole.
And you're wonderful.
(SCOFFS)
Miss, may I help you?
Uh, yes.
I'm here for, uh...
Mr. Jang.
Yes, um...
Who should I say is here?
Richard.
Um, Richard sent me.
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
What is your name?
No, Richard.
Richard's... He's just
looking for a place to park.
(CONTINUES SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Mr. Jang still wants
to know your name.
Lucy.
Lucy what?
Just Lucy. If he could be
quick, because I have to...
Just a second while I translate.
Mr. Jang is on his way.
Stay right here.
Can I sit?
Mr. Jang said you need
to stay right here.
I think it's better
if you stay right here.
(PHONE RINGING) Excuse me.
Regent Hotel.
(CONCIERGE SPEAKING MANDARIN)
(GUNSHOTS)
No!
(SPEAKS MANDARIN)
(MAN SPEAKS MANDARIN)
(GASPS)
No!
(LUCY GRUNTING)
(CRYING) Please. Please!
LUCY: Please!
I don't know anything!
Please! Please!
(LUCY SOBBING)
(MAN SPEAKS KOREAN)
(RETCHING)
(LUCY COUGHS)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
No! Please!
MAN: Hmm.
(SIGHS)
Do you speak English?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Lucy! Yes, I'm Lucy.
This has just been
a terrible mistake.
I'm just supposed
to deliver this case.
If you lost the key, you don't
have to chop off my hand.
(VOICE BREAKING) You can
just cut the chain, okay?
Please.
I'm begging you, please.
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
No, no, no!
(LUCY STRUGGLING)
(CRYING) Please.
Please!
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
TRANSLATOR: Hello, miss. I speak English.
I translate for Mr. Jang.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
Please tell him that I haven't done
anything. I don't know anything.
It's all just a big mistake, okay?
Please tell him that.
Yes, okay, okay. Hold on.
(TRANSLATOR SPEAKING KOREAN)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Mr. Jang wants to know
what's in the case.
No, I don't know
Do you speak English
or don't you speak English?
Yes, I do. I studied one year at
International High School in New York.
Okay.
Richard gave me the case to
give to you, that's all I know.
Okay? Please tell him that.
(TRANSLATOR SPEAKING KOREAN)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
He gave me a paper with numbers
written on it. What is this?
It's the code to open the case.
What's really in here?
Nothing dangerous.
So why won't he open it himself?
(TRANSLATOR SPEAKING KOREAN)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
He doesn't trust
Mr. Richard.
I don't trust Richard, either.
I only dated him for a week.
(TRANSLATOR SPEAKING KOREAN)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
(SHOUTING)
Okay, okay, okay.
Mr. Jang insists that you open the case.
Okay, okay.
(SOBBING) Please, God, help me.
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
He wants you to hurry up.
Mr. Jang has
other things to do.
(GASPS)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Can you describe
the contents of the case?
It's four plastic pouches filled
with a blue powder. Like a...
Maybe a purple powder.
I don't know.
It looks gross.
(TRANSLATOR SPEAKING KOREAN)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
(MAN SPEAKING KOREAN)
(INHALES)
(COUGHS AND WHEEZES)
(PANTING)
(LAUGHING)
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
(GASPS)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
(GASPING)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
TRANSLATOR: Mr. Jang wants
to offer you a job.
A job?
(CRYING) I don't want a job.
NORMAN: If life starts
approximately a billion years ago,
we will have to
wait 400,000 years
to see the aberration
of the first nerve cells.
This is where life
as we know it begins.
Brains in formation of
only a few milligrams.
It's not possible to determine
any sign of intelligence yet.
It acts more as a reflex.
One neuron, you're alive.
Two neurons,
you're moving,
and with movement,
interesting things
begin to happen.
(VARIOUS ANIMALS CRYING OUT)
Animal life on Earth goes
back millions of years.
Yet most species only use 3 to
5% of its cerebral capacity.
But it isn't until we
reached human beings
at the top of the animal chain
that we finally see a species use
more of its cerebral capacity.
(GRUNTING)
10% may not seem like much,
but it's a lot if you look
at all we've done with it.
(GRUNTING)
NORMAN: Now let's discuss
a special case.
The only living being that
uses its brain better than us.
The dolphin.
It is estimated that
this incredible animal
uses up to 20%
of its cerebral capacity.
In particular,
this allows it
to have an echolocation system
that is more efficient than any
sonar invented by mankind.
But the dolphin did not invent the
sonar, it developed it naturally.
And this is
the crucial part of our
philosophical reflection
we have today.
Can we therefore conclude
that humans are
concerned more with
having
than being?
(SIRENS WAILING IN DISTANCE)
(GROANS)
(PANTING)
(SIGHS)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
(MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
Lucy.
What did you do to my stomach?
MAN: Nothing!
Just a little (SNIFFLING)
horizontal slit.
It's very well done.
And you'll find within a month,
the scar is
practically invisible.
So, you'll be able to show your
tummy off on the beach next summer.
I don't care about the scar.
(STAMMERING) Is it why
we opened you up, yeah?
Rest assured, we didn't harvest
your organs or anything.
We merely slipped a little
package into your lower tummy.
It's a new drug
that kids in Europe
are going to love, believe me.
What is it?
Well, the scientific
term is C.P.H.4.
Which is not very sexy
from a sales point of view.
So we're still working on
something with a bit more pop.
Any suggestions?
Ah!
Excuse me.
Welcome!
Welcome, come on in.
Lovely! Oops!
Splendid, splendid!
(THE LIMEY LAUGHS)
Marvelous! Lovely, lovely.
Oh!
How are you?
MAN: Very good, my dear.
THE LIMEY: Okay.
Right. Um...
First of all,
many thanks for taking
part in this enterprise,
which I'm sure will
go off flawlessly.
These lovely
passports and tickets
will enable you to return
home in the next 24 hours.
Now, upon arrival, you will be
taken in hand by our people,
so that we might
recover our merchandise
and you might
rediscover the freedom
which you so richly deserve.
I'm sure I don't
need to remind you,
but for any of those
who may be tempted
to warn or turn themselves
in to the authorities,
we have the names and addresses
of the families
of every one of you,
down to the most
distant cousins, right?
(COUGHS)
So, we rely, therefore,
on your complete discretion.
Good!
(CLEARS THROAT) Anyway,
gentlemen, madam, allow me
to be the first to wish you
bon voyage!
Oops. (CHUCKLES)
Lovely.
You're gonna sell this?
I'm afraid it's
our business model.
NORMAN: For primitive beings like us, life
seems to have only one single purpose,
gaining time.
And it is going through
time that seems to be also
the only real purpose of each
of the cells in our bodies.
To achieve that aim,
the mass of the cells
that make up earthworms
and human beings
has only two solutions.
Be immortal
or to reproduce.
If its habitat is not
sufficiently favorable
or nurturing...
The cell will
choose immortality.
In other words, self-sufficiency
and self-management.
On the other hand,
if the habitat is favorable...
They will choose to reproduce.
That way, when they die,
they hand down essential
information and knowledge
to the next cell, which hands it
down to the next cell and so on.
Thus, knowledge and learning
are handed down through time.
LUCY: Okay, okay.
Keep calm.
You have to wait.
Just play for time.
You'll have time to think
it through on the plane.
Just take the flight.
Take the flight,
get out of here.
That's the main thing right now.
Just save time.
Don't try anything. Keep your cool.
You're alive.
You're alive, babe.
That's all that matters.
Just wait.
Save time.
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
I'm not in the mood.
(MEN SPEAKING MANDARIN)
(MAN GRUNTING)
(LUCY GROANING)
(SHOUTING IN MANDARIN)
(WHIMPERING)
(COUGHS)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
(PANTING)
NORMAN: Let's imagine
for a few moments
what our life would be like if
we could access, let's say,
20% of our brain's capacity.
This first stage
would give us access to
and control of our own body.
Sir?
Yes.
Has it been
proved scientifically?
For the moment, it's just
hypothesis, I confess.
But if you think about it,
it's troubling to
realize that the Greeks,
the Egyptians and the Indians
had notion of cells
centuries before
the invention of the microscope.
And what to say about Darwin,
whom everybody took for a fool
when he put forth
his theory of evolution.
It's up to us to push
the rules and laws
and go from
evolution to revolution.
(ALL LAUGH)
100 billion neurons per human,
of which only 15% are activated.
There are more connections
in the human body
than there are
stars in the galaxy.
We possess a gigantic
network of information
to which we have
almost no access.
Sir?
Yes.
And what will be the next stage?
Well, the next stage would probably
be control of other people.
But for that, we
would need to access
at least 40%
of our brain's capacity.
After control of
ourselves and others
would come control of matter.
But now we're entering into
the realm of science fiction
and we don't know any more than
a dog who watches the moon.
Excuse me, sir.
Yes.
But what would happen if,
for some reason we ignore,
somebody unlocked 100% of
their cerebral capacity?
100%?
Yes.
I have no idea.
(DOOR UNLOCKS)
Ahhh!
(MEN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Hey!
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Hey! You speak English?
No, no, no.
Ahhh!
You speak English?
Yes, yes.
Take me to the hospital now.
Hospital.
(INJURED CABBIE SPEAKING MANDARIN)
My leg!
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Hospital!
Wait for me.
SURGEON: Miss! Hello?
Hey! Miss!
I need help.
It's urgent.
You cannot be in here.
We are operating!
Please, get out!
(GASPS)
(NURSE SCREAMS)
You wouldn't have been
able to save him anyway.
The tumor had already
invaded the cortex
and the right side of his spine.
Somebody put
a bag of drugs in me.
I need you to remove it.
It's leaking.
Do it now.
Right. I'll just administer
a local anesthetic.
Don't bother.
Right.
Okay.
Calm down, please.
Put the gun down.
I'm just going to examine, okay?
Do you mind?
No.
(DIALING)
(LINE RINGING)
WOMAN: Hello?
Mom?
Hey! Lucy.
Baby, it's great
to hear from you!
But what time is it over there?
I don't know, it's night.
Hold on a Sec, let me get
rid of the other line.
I'm going to have to go inside.
I'm back. You're not partying
too much, are you?
You promised me you'd
look after yourself.
I'm trying to, Mom.
I am trying to.
Well, thanks for calling
out of the blue like this.
Your father's gonna
be sad he missed you.
He isn't home from the gym yet.
Usually, you call us
in the morning.
Mom?
Yes?
I feel everything.
What do you mean, sweetie?
Space,
the air,
the vibrations,
the people.
I can feel the gravity.
I can feel the rotation
of the Earth,
the heat leaving my body,
the blood in my veins.
I can feel my brain,
the deepest parts
of my memory...
(LINE CRACKLING) Sweetie, we have a bad
connection. I can't hear you so well.
What did you say about memory?
The pain in my mouth
when I had braces.
I can remember the feeling
of your hand
on my forehead
when I ran a fever.
I remember stroking
the cat, it was so soft.
The cat? What cat, honey?
A Siamese with blue eyes
and a broken tail.
Sweetie, you can't
possibly remember that.
You were barely a year old.
I remember the taste
of your milk in my mouth.
The room,
the liquid...
Sweetie, what are you
talking about?
I just wanna tell
you that I love you,
Mom and Dad.
Sweetie...
And I wanna thank you
for the thousand kisses
that I can still
feel on my face.
I love you, Mom.
I love you, too, sweetie.
More than anything in the world.
How much is left?
500 grams.
And how long
will it take my body
to eliminate the rest of it?
To answer that, I need
to know what it is.
May I?
Go ahead.
C.P.H.4.
Tell me about it.
Pregnant women
manufacture C.P.H.4
in the sixth week of pregnancy
in tiny quantities.
For a baby, it packs the
power of an atomic bomb.
It's what gives the fetus
the necessary energy to form
all the bones in its body.
I'd heard they tried to make
a synthetic version of it.
I didn't realize
that they'd succeeded.
If it really is C.P.H.4,
in this quantity,
I'm amazed you're still alive.
Not for long.
(SIGHS)
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING ON HEADPHONES)
(GROANING)
Learning's always
a painful process.
Like when you're little
and your bones
are growing
and you ache all over.
Can you believe I can remember
the sound of my own
bones growing?
Like this grinding
under the skin.
Everything's different now.
Like, sounds are music that
I can understand, like fluids.
It's funny,
I used to be so concerned
with who I was
and what I wanted to be
and now that I have access
to the furthest reaches
of my brain,
I see things clearly
and realize that
what makes us us
it's primitive.
They're all obstacles.
Does that make any sense?
Like this pain
you're experiencing.
It's blocking you
from understanding.
All you know now is pain.
That's all you know, pain.
Where are the others?
The others carrying the drugs.
I need the rest of it,
for medicinal purposes.
(CONTINUES GROANING)
Berlin.
Paris.
Rome.
Thank you for sharing.
(SHUDDERING)
(SCREAMING)
Oh. Evening, Professor.
Bonsoir, Albert.
Do we have you
for dinner tonight?
I'm afraid so.
I'm exhausted.
Have a good rest.
Thank you.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(SNARLS)
You scared the shit out of me,
ringing that bell
like some nutbar!
I missed you.
Me, too.
Yeah, you lose your
keys or something?
Yeah.
Can I borrow your laptop?
Yeah, of course.
So I spent all of yesterday in
auditions, which are awesome.
They just have you
standing around all day
because they don't give a shit about
your time gabbing away in Chinese.
Who understands Chinese?
I don't understand Chinese.
And then they say they're always
gonna call, and they never do,
because they don't even
take your phone number.
Except this one guy,
but he's not Chinese.
He works at the agency
and he's cute.
Oh, my God, he's cute.
In the cute-and-I-kinda-know-it
kinda way.
Like he had this thing...
Oh, my God, and his ass!
Phew! Let me
get started on that!
And you are never gonna
guess where he took me.
BOTH: Four Seasons, Royal Suites,
and we made love all night.
I'm sorry, I'm talking about myself.
What's up? How's Richard?
He's dead.
You guys are crazy.
I'm gonna take a shower.
(PHONE RINGING)
Yes?
LUCY: Professor Norman,
my name's Lucy.
I just read all your
research on the human brain.
We need to meet.
(CHUCKLES)
All of my research?
Well, I'm very flattered,
young lady,
but I find that hard to believe.
I must have written
no less than...
6,734 pages. I can recite them
to you all by heart, if you wish.
Are you one of Emily's friends?
This sounds like one of her silly jokes.
Is she there with you?
No, I'm all on my own.
Who are you?
I just told you.
Uh...
Lucy, right?
Yes, sorry.
I read your theory on the use
of the brain's capacity.
It's a little rudimentary,
but you're on the right track.
Thank you.
Professor, my cells are reproducing
at a phenomenal speed.
Several million per second.
I'm having trouble precisely
evaluating the time of my death,
but I doubt I'll last
more than 24 hours.
What are you talking about?
What I'm saying is that your
theory is not a theory.
I absorbed a large quantity
of synthetic C.P.H.4.
that will allow me to use
100% of my cerebral capacity.
Right now, I'm at 28%,
and what you wrote is true.
Once the brain reaches 20%, it
opens up and expands the rest.
There are no more obstacles.
They fall away like dominoes.
I'm colonizing my own brain.
Well, (CLEARS THROAT)
I don't know what to... Say.
It's true, I've been working on
this theory for over 20 years,
but it's only ever been
hypotheses and research ideas.
I never thought anyone would...
You can control
your own metabolism?
Yes.
And I can start to control
other people's bodies.
Also, I can control
magnetic and electric waves.
Not all of them,
just the most basic.
Television.
Telephone.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Radio.
(RADIO SWITCHING STATIONS)
That's amazing.
I don't feel pain,
fear,
desire.
It's like all things that make
us human are fading away.
It's like the less human I feel,
all this knowledge
about everything,
quantum physics,
applied mathematics,
the infinite capacity
of a cell's nucleus.
They're all exploding inside
my brain, all this knowledge.
I don't know what to do with it.
If you're asking me
what to do...
You know,
if you think about
the very nature of life,
I mean, from the very beginning,
the development
of the first cell
that divided into two cells.
The sole purpose
of life has been
to pass on what was learned.
There was no higher purpose.
So if you're asking me
what to do
with all this knowledge
you're accumulating,
I'd say
pass it on.
Just like any simple cell
going through time.
Time.
Yes, of course.
I'll be at your
door in 12 hours.
You're leaving?
Yes.
What is this?
A prescription.
Since when did you
start writing in Chinese?
Since an hour ago.
Luce, I don't
understand any of this.
Your kidneys aren't functioning
efficiently, your liver's failing you.
You need to make
some lifestyle changes.
Take this medication,
work out, eat organic.
You'll be okay.
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
Last night, at 11 Pm,
a woman shot a patient dead.
It happened at
Tri-Service Hospital.
The suspect is 25,
blonde, medium height.
Police are hunting nationwide.
She is armed and dangerous.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(PHONE RINGING)
Del Rio.
(MAN ON PHONE SPEAKING FRENCH)
I've got a weird call
from a US citizen in Taiwan.
A young woman calling to tip us off
about a big drugs ring.
- I'll take it.
- I'll tape you.
DEL RIO: Hello?
I have important information about
a group of drug traffickers.
I need to speak with someone
in a position of authority.
Aha.
You're very lucky,
there's no one
with more authority
in this office than me.
But let's start at the beginning.
What is your name?
Listen up, Pierre Del Rio.
Get off your desk,
sit in your chair,
pick up the red pen
to the left of you
and take down everything I say.
There are no cameras.
Hurry up!
I've no time to waste.
Go ahead.
I'm gonna be sending
you the details
of three people about
to arrive in Europe.
Each one is carrying
a kilo of drugs.
I need you to arrest them
and collect the substance.
I'll need it for later.
What form are these
drugs in? Bars? Capsules?
Powder. Hidden in plastic pouches
inside their intestines.
Excuse me?
Make sure to be careful
when you remove them.
The product is very powerful.
(BARKS)
(WHIMPERING)
Believe me.
(COMPUTER BEEPING)
Got it?
Yeah.
Good.
I'm counting on you.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Okay?
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Good morning.
That's him!
Pick him up.
Come with me, please.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Hello.
Sir, come with us.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Welcome to Rome.
Good morning, sir.
Please, follow me.
This way.
Yeah, sure.
(OFFICERS SHOUTING)
(PEOPLE GASPING)
(PHONE RINGING)
Del Rio.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Thanks for calling me back.
We took delivery
of your package.
Thanks very much.
I'll send you the paperwork
for the transfer.
Bye.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Okay, we got all three.
(BEEPING) WOMAN ON PA: Ladies and gentlemen,
we are now beginning our descent
to Paris Charles de Gaulle.
(TYPING RAPIDLY ON KEYBOARD)
Miss, I have to ask you to
put away your computers now.
You should wipe your nose.
Excuse me?
May I have a glass of champagne?
Um, yes. Of course.
Could you bring some champagne
to the girl over there?
Yeah, I just have a nosebleed.
Miss, your champagne.
Thank you.
I'm very sorry, but you really
need to close your table now.
Sure.
To knowledge.
If the habitat is not sufficiently
favorable or nurturing...
(COUGHING)
The cell will
choose immortality.
In other words, self-sufficiency
and self-management.
(GRUNTS)
No! Miss, miss!
You must remain seated!
Miss!
(SCREAMS)
MAN: Miss! Open the door! You really
have to go back to your seat!
We're gonna land soon.
Please! Open the door.
Please, say something.
Are you okay? Miss?
Miss, please, open the door!
Please do something,
help me! Please!
We're gonna land soon!
Open the door!
(LUCY GROANING) Miss! Are you okay?
Say something!
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
With a scar
on her lower abdomen?
Pretty recent,
with thread in it.
- How is she?
- Fine. She's sleeping.
With the shot I gave her,
she'll be out all day.
(MACHINE BEEPING)
(GROANS)
(BONES CRACK)
(MACHINE BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(BEEPING SLOWS)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
- She's awake!
- Are you sure?
She's sitting on the bed.
That's her.
- You didn't restrain her?
- Sure, we did!
Miss!
Don't move.
I need to talk to you alone.
And I need you to put
your hands up, please.
Did you get the packets?
Yes.
Where are they?
They're safe.
Here,
in Paris.
They'll be safer in my hands.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Don't leave the car there.
Park it up.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
You know, as a cop you see
some pretty weird shit.
But I have to be
honest with you.
What you did back there,
that freaked me out.
To put everyone
to sleep like that.
Do I need to be worried?
No.
Good.
(INDISTINCT VOICES CHATTERING)
(MAN'S VOICE GROWS LOUDER)
Do you mind?
No.
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
What's that?
Korean. I'm gonna drive.
Hey! No, no, no.
This is a police car!
You can't. No, this is
not possible, lady.
This is a police car.
Okay, okay.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Let's go, guys!
Sir, sir, excuse me, sir.
I need to talk to somebody.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Talk to the police.
Look, I'm a German citizen and
I demand to see a lawyer.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
I'll check with Surgery.
- Grab us some food.
- You're a foodaholic.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Do you always drive like that?
I've never driven before.
Great.
Hey, that's one-way.
We're late.
Hey, I'd rather be
late than dead.
We never really die.
Sorry, sir.
I don't feel good.
(MAN GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
I'm fine. I'm fine.
(CARS HONKING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
I'm gonna tell them
to stop following us.
Don't bother.
(BEEPING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
I got you bacon...
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Give me the case.
(LAUGHS)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Kill her and get the pouch.
(GRUNTS)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Don't stand there, kill her!
Ahhh!
(GROANING)
Open it.
(SQUELCHING)
Let's go.
I'm not sure I could
be of any help for you.
Yes, you are.
What for?
A reminder.
Shall we go?
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
Where are we going?
ELECTRONIC VOICE: Take the first left.
Okay.
(OFFICER SPEAKING FRENCH)
Move!
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Follow that car.
(CELL PHONE RINGING) Professor?
Hello?
Lucy.
Oh! It's her! It's her!
Hey, you.
You're in Paris?
Yes, I am.
Good, good! Excellent.
So, look, I am no longer
at the hotel now.
I have come to the university,
where I've taken the liberty
of calling together a few of my
colleagues to discuss your case.
Top minds in their field
and very trustworthy.
I trust you.
Oh, thank you.
So, do you think
you could meet us
here at the university?
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
I'm, uh...
I'm very pleased to meet you.
Likewise.
Captain Del Rio.
How do you do?
Um...
Let me introduce
you to my colleagues.
This is Professor Cartier,
neurosurgeon.
I know who everyone is.
Of course.
Gentlemen, this is Lucy,
the first woman to...
I mean...
As I mentioned earlier,
Miss Lucy has,
for reasons that
remain a mystery to me,
unlocked certain
portions of her brain
that offer access to
previously unexplored
cerebral zones.
She has abilities.
Can you give us an example?
Your daughter,
Gabrielle, age six,
died in a car accident.
It was a blue car,
leather seats,
plastic bird hanging from the
rear view mirror. (GIRL LAUGHING)
(SOBBING)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Boss, 5 men down at the hospital.
Sorry.
How many men left?
I have about 25 with me.
That damn girl,
she doesn't give in.
She's a witch.
I know that.
I'll kill her myself.
There are men coming here.
Can you secure the room?
I need to stay focused.
Sure.
(SIRENS WAILING)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Speed it up.
(OFFICERS SHOUTING)
How did you manage to access
all this information?
Electrical impulses.
Every cell knows and talks
to every other cell.
They exchange a thousand bits of
information between them per second.
Cells group together, forming
a giant web of communication,
which in turn forms matter.
Cells get together,
take on one form,
deform, reform.
Makes no difference,
it's all the same.
Humans consider
themselves unique,
so they've rooted
their whole theory
of existence on
their uniqueness.
"One" is their unit of measure.
But it's not.
All social systems we've put
into place are a mere sketch.
One plus one equals two.
That's all we've learned.
But one plus one
has never equaled two.
There are, in fact,
no numbers and no letters.
We've codified our existence
to bring it down to human size
to make it comprehensible.
We've created a scale so that we
can forget its unfathomable scale.
But if humans are
not the unit of measure
and the world isn't governed
by mathematical laws,
what governs all that?
Film a car speeding down a road.
Speed up the image infinitely
and the car disappears.
So what proof do we
have of its existence?
Time gives legitimacy
to its existence.
Time is the only
true unit of measure.
It gives proof to
the existence of matter.
Without time,
we don't exist.
Time is unity.
(ALARMS BLARING)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Search the whole building
and find her!
We won't be able to
hold them for much longer.
Time to go then.
Are you sure you
need such huge doses?
I'm afraid you won't survive.
Some cells inside me will fight
and defend their integrity
till the very end.
In order to attain the last few
percent, I have to force it
to crack the cells open
to their nucleus.
(SIGHS)
But all of this
knowledge, Lucy...
I'm not even sure that
mankind is ready for it.
We're so driven by
power and profit.
Given man's nature,
it might bring us only
instability and chaos.
Ignorance brings chaos,
not knowledge.
I'll build a computer and
download all my knowledge in it.
I'll find a way for you
to have access to it.
Yeah.
I just hope we will be
worthy of your sacrifice.
Nobody move!
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
Do you understand English?
(GUNFIRE)
(GASPING)
PROFESSOR: What is she doing?
NORMAN: She's looking
for energy and matter.
And she's trying to connect
with our computers.
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Chong-Ju!
I'm here, boss.
Do something about them.
Okay, boss!
You guys, come on.
Ready?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
You okay?
Get a medic. Fast!
PROFESSOR 1: Oh, my God.
What's happening?
PROFESSOR 2: What is she making?
New generation computer,
I presume.
(SHOUTING IN FRENCH)
(INDISTINCT VOICES CHATTERING)
(TROLLEY BELL RINGING)
(HORSE NEIGHING)
(DISTANT SCREECHING)
(GRUNTING)
(ROARING)
(HUFFING)
(SNARLS)
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Where is she?
Answer me.
Answer me!
Hey, you!
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
PROFESSOR: Look.
The computer, it's moving.
DEL RIO: Hey.
Where is she?
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
LUCY: Life was given to
us a billion years ago.
Now you know what to do with it.